伙计们 开始行动了
Fellas, it's go time.
呈战龟队形 三 二 一
Turtle Formation in three, two, one!
战龟队形怎么成这样了
What happened to Turtle Formation?
战龟队形
Wait, Turtle Formation?
我还以为你说松鼠队形呢
I thought you said "Squirrel Formation."
他怎么可能说什么松鼠队形呢
Why would he say "Squirrel..." What's "Squirrel Formation"?
伙计们 别吵了 该走了
Guys, chill out. Let's go!
拉斐尔 准备着陆
Hey, Raph, do that thing.
不 那样太疼了
No. I don't want to do it. It hurts.
快点儿
Do it, do it, do it...
我停不下来 快点儿
Won't stop until you do it, do it, do it.
好吧 行了
Okay, fine!
耶
Yeah!
- 多尼 - 开始吧
- Donnie! - Here we go!
你定好了 是吗
You set it up, right?
对 没问题的 我保证
Yeah, he'll be there, I promise.
闻着好香 谢谢你 凯文 下周再见
Smells delicious. Thanks, Kevin. See you next week!
快 快 快
Go, go, go!
伙计们 还是老规矩 拿到那盒子
Guys, you know the drill. Let's get that box.
给我拿来吧
Give me that.
(莱昂纳多 队长)
- 这边儿 - 接着
- Over here! - Keep away!
(拉斐尔 大力士)
拉斐尔 传回来
Raph, over here!
我再传给你
Right back at you.
- 我接住了 - 嘿
- I'll take that. - Hey!
(多尼 高智商)
(麦奇 比萨爱好者)
伙计们 我们来的时间刚刚好
All right, guys. We made it just in time!
反攻啊 快点儿 反攻
Make the move. Come on, make the move.
- 耶 - 耶
- Yeah! - Yeah! Yeah!
- 耶 - 看到了吗
- Yeah! - You see that?
伙计们 我说加油 你们说尼克斯加油
All right, I say, "Go!" You say, "Knicks!"
- 加油 - 尼克斯加油
- Go! Go! - Knicks! Knicks!
来个三分球
Two points coming up!
投篮
Shoot it!
伙计们 这太有意思了
Guys, does it get any better than this?
是啊 兄弟 真想到下面去看
Yeah, but I want to be down there.
得了吧 就你那丑样下去还不把人吓跑了
You sit your ugly self down there, you'd have people running for their lives.
其实我很帅的 老兄
You see me? I look good, brah.
伙计们
Yo, fellas! Hey, hey, hey.
我们这里可是最好的位置了
We got the best seats in the house right here.
为什么要下去看呢
Anyone can sit down there.
我们拯救了纽约
We saved this city.
应该出现在屏幕上而不是屏幕后面
We should be on the Jumbotron, not in it.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
一年前 我们的城市被阴影所笼罩
one year ago, a shadow fell over our city.
(麦迪逊广场花园 尼克斯队)
我们突然遭到了臭名昭著的歹徒史莱德的攻击
Suddenly, it was under siege by the notorious villain, Shredder.
在他凶恶的爪牙大脚帮的协助下
Along with his army of enforcers, the Foot Clan,
史莱德占领了我们的街道
Shredder ruled our streets.
直到有一天
Until one day,
从黑暗之中走出了一位光明的使者
from out of the shadows, stepped a beacon of hope.
他说的是谁
Hey, you see who that is?
他只不过是一位普通的摄像师
He was just a humble cameraman.
但是当危险袭击城市心脏的时候
But when danger struck the heart of our city,
他以一己之力打败了史莱德 成功地将他送进了监狱
he sin gle-handedly battled Shredder, locking him up behind bars.
现在大家请看球场的边缘
And now, turn your attention courtside
本周晚些时候
where Jill Martin meets a man who, later this week,
他将获赠象征荣誉市民的金钥匙
will receive an honorary key to the city.
让我们有请 猎鹰弗恩·芬威克
Please welcome Vern "The Falcon" Fenwick!
弗恩
Vern,
跟粉丝们说说 像你这样的普通市民
tell the fans how a regular New Yorker like yourself
是怎么做到一个人单挑史莱德
was able to sin gle-handedly
并且成功地把他绳之以法的
hunt Shredder down and bring him to justice.
实际上 吉尔
Well, the truth is, Jill,
我得到了几个朋友的帮助
I actually had help from a couple of friends.
快看啊 他马上要说到我们了
No way! He's totally gonna give us props.
快点儿说呀
Here it comes! Here it comes!
雷霆和闪电
Thunder and Lightning!
耶
Yeah!
- 搞什么 - 为什么
- Come on! - What is this?
伙计们 大家都知道我们不可能从这件事中得到奖赏
Guys, you know we couldn't take credit for bringing down Shredder.
弗恩也只是在遵守我们跟他达成的协议
Vern's just sticking to the arrangement we made with him.
好吧
Yeah, well,
一个协议就把我们晾在
this arrangement has us spending the rest of our lives
这高得让人头疼的鬼地方
sitting in the nosebleeds.
让他也疼一下
Speaking of nosebleeds...
- 你干什么 - 等等
- Hey, what'd you take? - Hold on. Hold on.
你当心点儿 那是我的玩具枪
Hey, be careful with that, that's my peashooter.
好了 脑袋 就打脑袋
Okay, hold on. Head shot. Straight head shot.
能打中吗
You got this.
瞄准点儿 好
You got this! Yeah.
我只是想为所有纽约人做一个榜样
So I just wanted to be an example for all New Yorkers.
一个人
One man...
打中了
You got him!
你没事吧
Are you... Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
该我了
My turn, my turn, my turn.
好的 看你的了
All right. All right. You got this.
好吧 谢谢你接受我的采访
Okay. Thanks so much for joining us.
猎鹰弗恩·芬威克 女士们 先生们
Vern "The Falcon" Fenwick, everybody!
笨蛋 猎鹰
Take that, Falcon!
刚才怎么回事
What happened out there?
爱普尔
Hey, April.
你怎么了 没事 我在锻炼呢
April! Hey! What's up, April? Nothing, I've been working out.
多尼 听我说 我正在纽约中央车站
Donnie, listen to me. I'm at Grand Central Station
跟踪巴克斯特·斯多克曼博士
staking out Dr. Baxter Stockman.
巴克斯特·斯多克曼
Baxter Stockman!
15岁麻省理工学院毕业 拥有134项专利
He graduated MIT at 15. He's got 134 patents.
目前是T.C.R.I.的首席科学家
He's the lead scientist for TCRI.
我的偶像 他简直是个天才
Big fan. The man's a genius.
对 正因为他是个天才 所以麻烦大了
Yeah, well, he's a genius that's about to be in a lot of trouble.
听着 我认为巴克斯特·斯多克曼在为史莱德工作
Look, I think Baxter Stockman is working with Shredder.
史莱德 需要帮忙吗
Shredder. Do you need us there?
不 我自己能搞定
Nah. Baxter is a softie.
你还记不记得你送我的那件生日礼物
But, you know, that birthday present that you made for me?
手表 记得
The watch, yeah.
我想用它黑进巴克斯特的邮箱
I want to use it to try and hack into Baxter's emails.
可以 爱普尔 不过如果要想黑进他的账户
Okay, April, but if you're going to hack into his accounts,
- 就得靠近他 - 要多近
- you'll need to get close. - How close?
你的表要在他的设备三英尺之内
Your watch needs to be within three feet of his device,
iPad iPhone什么的
iPad, iPhone, whatever.
明白了 多谢你的指导
Got it. Good looking out, buddy.
一会儿再聊
Talk to you soon.
这边请 先生
Here you are, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
(超出范围)
打扰了
Excuse me.
抱歉 你就是
Sorry. It's just... Aren't you...
尽管我很愿意有位像你这样的女性朋友
As much as I'd like to be someone that a girl like you would recognize,
但是很遗憾 你认错人了
I can assure you you don't know who I am.
你是巴克斯特·斯多克曼哲学博士
You're Baxter Stockman. PhD.
15岁就从麻省理工毕业了
Graduated from MIT at 15 years old.
你在T.C.R.I.发明的纳米机器人对我来说
Your innovations in nanorobotics at TCRI
简直太有启发了
have been truly inspirational for me.
不好意思 我有点儿像书呆子
I'm so sorry. I'm just like... I'm a nerd!
不 别拘束 很幽默 继续
No, please. Geek out. Please.
- 真的 - 当然
- Really? - Yeah.
- 谢谢你 - 耶
- Thank you. - Yeah.
当然 实际上还是不一样的
Actually, though, there's a big difference.
书呆子不一定幽默
I'm a nerd, not a geek.
其中的差别就好像是指环王和哈利波特
It's the difference between, like, Lord of the Rings and Harry Potter.
TED演讲和
Or TED Talks and...
动漫节
Comic-Con! Yeah.
对
Yeah.
斯多克曼博士 已经得到确认了 先生
Dr. Stockman. We just got confirmation, sir.
货物今晚肯定会发出
The "package" is shipping later tonight.
确保他们盯紧每一个环节
Well, make sure they're tracking it every step of the way.
还有 特雷弗 今晚别再来打扰我
And, Trevor, I'm done working for the day.
那么 不好意思我得接个电话 是我男朋友 抱歉
I just have to take this. Really quick. It's my boyfriend. I'm sorry.
你有男朋友了
You have a boyfriend.
有男朋友了 但是你男朋友知道
Of course you do. But does your boyfriend know
圆周率小数点儿
the difference between pi to the third decimal point,
后面第3位和第15位数字的区别吗
and pi to the fifteenth decimal point?
遇到你真是太荣幸了
It has truly been an honor to meet you.
你真是我们这个时代最伟大的思想家之一
And you are really one of the greatest minds of our generation.
再见
Bye.
快看 正宗的西部牛仔
Look, everybody. I got a cowboy.
看看多强壮啊 是不是啊
Look at those muscles, am I right?
一起说 茄子
Cheese!
瞧瞧你们 简直太热情了
There's so many of you.
防守
Defense! Defense! Defense!
跳球
Jump ball!
不可能 我的脚踩到了一块比萨
Jump ball! No way! It's pizza on my Nike! It's pizza!
是比萨 你看看 看看我的球鞋
Look at it. Look at my shoe.
这怎么解释 为什么会有比萨
Explain that to me. It's pizza on my Nike!
伙计 欢迎来到纽约
Hey, man, welcome to New York.
简直是太悬了
That was a close call.
我们再找个新地方继续看比赛 麦奇
We're gonna have to find a new spot to watch the game now, Mikey.
麦奇
Mikey!
麦奇 你在干什么
Mikey, what are you doing?
是万圣节游行 伙计
It's the Halloween parade, bro.
我一直想参加万圣节游行
I always wanted to be in the Halloween parade.
这应该是我们最放松的一天了
It's the one night of the year where we fit in.
麦奇 你就别做梦了
Mikey, we'll never fit in.
我们是忍者 生活在阴影里 我们走
We're ninjas. We live in the shadows. Let's go!
是啊 我们走
Yeah. Let's go.
酷啊
Cool.
打扮不错 朋友
Looking good, bro.
谢谢 朋友
Thanks, man.
麦奇
Mikey.
- 麦奇 - 又怎么了
- Mikey. - What's the problem?
这是我的城市 我是其中一员
This is my city. These are my people!
狂欢的纽约城
Is New York in the house?
简直是前所未有的经历
That was the most amazing thing ever!
我们的宗旨 忍者在黑暗中行动
What part of "ninjas move in the shadows"
难道你忘了吗
don't you understand?
爱普尔 情况怎么样
April! How'd it go?
多尼 我正在查看巴克斯特iPad里的数据
Donnie, I'm looking at the data from Baxter's iPad.
你黑进去了 发现什么了
Hey, you got in. What did you find?
等等 多尼 文件正在删除
Hold on, Donnie. The files are erasing.
应该是启动了自毁程序
It's some sort of self-destruct program.
正在删除
Erasing?
文件被删除前
Before they started erasing
我已经看到了巴克斯特的两封邮件 我猜测是对的
I had a chance to read a couple of Baxter's emails, and I was right.
巴克斯特在为大脚帮工作
Baxter is working with the Foot Clan.
史莱德今晚要被转押到纽约远郊的监狱去
Shredder is being transported to a prison in upstate New York tonight.
大脚帮计划袭击押送车辆
And the Foot Clan are planning on hitting the convoy.
他们要把他从警察的手中救出来
They're gonna break him out of police custody.
继续为非作歹
He'll be free again!
谁 多尼
Who, Donnie?
史莱德
Shredder.
比博
Beebs.
好了
Okay.
琼斯
Hey, Jones.
都交给你了
They're all yours.
感觉怎么样 犯罪大王
What up, Big Daddy Law Breaker?
我代表全体纽约人对你说声再见
On behalf of the people of New York, welcome to The Big Good-bye.
你已经冥想了将近24个小时了
You have meditated for nearly 24 hours.
十秒钟之内 你将到达极乐世界 生命将得到彻底的升华
In ten seconds you will reach nirvana and total spiritual enlightenment.
十 九
Ten, nine...
- 5 4 3 2 - 快快快
- Five, four, three, two... - Go, go, go!
不好意思 我说等一下
Excuse me. All right, slow down.
没有人想解释一下吗
Does somebody want to explain?
师傅 大脚帮想要劫囚车救史莱德
Sensei, the Foot Clan are attempting to break Shredder out of custody.
如果他重获自由
If Shredder is free,
这个城市又将笼罩在他的恐怖阴影之下
his reign of terror over the city will begin again.
- 的确如此 - 那眼下的问题就是
- Exactly. - Then there's only one question.
你为什么跟一个愤怒的老耗子在这儿浪费时间
Why are you wasting time talking toagrumpyold rat?
快去抓他
Go get him!
谢谢老爸
Thanks, Dad.
好了 伙计们 别太激动了 这还是个半成品呢
Okay, guys, don't get too excited. It's still a work in progress.
兄弟
Dude!
不是开玩笑吧 这
Are you kidding me?
听我说 伙计们 还有很多地方需要改进
I'm telling you guys, a lot of tweaking still required.
完工之后会更棒的
But when it's done, it's gonna be amazing.
可惜现在没时间了
Well, no time like the present.
电线就这么露在外面
All these wires are still bunched up here.
一点章法都没有
There's no organization to any of this.
我拿着红色的 你拿着黄色的
I've got red wires, I've got yellow wires...
你看看 焊点还没完成呢
As you can see, the spot welding's not done yet...
- 座椅也不能放倒 - 多尼 多尼
- The seats don't recline... - Donnie! Donnie!
好了 史莱德的囚车在东北偏东7.2英里
All right, Shredder's convoy is 7.2 miles east-northeast.
追上去
Punch it!
他们改变了时间表
They moved the timeline up.
开始了 史莱德正在路上
Here we go. Sensei Shredder's on the move.
实时监控已经链接
Surveillance feed is live.
标准的押送队形
Standard transport formation.
这些家伙真没有创意
These guys are so predictable.
史莱德
Hey, Shredder!
你被指控犯下32项一级谋杀罪
You got 32 counts of first-degree murder.
混蛋
Hot damn!
你可真是个杀人恶魔
You are one mean son of a bitch.
像你这样特别容易
And take it from someone who has his own problems
情绪失控的家伙
with anger management issues,
最需要的是培养一份业余爱好
you, my friend, seriously need a hobby.
我的爱好是打冰球
I myself am a hockey guy.
在冰场上横冲直撞
I like my bone crushing on ice.
你喜欢冰球吗
You like hockey, right?
不 我喜欢自由搏击
No. I like cage fighting.
自由搏击 好吧
Cage fighting. Okay.
真是他
It's him.
别没大没小的
Hey, hey, hey, speak from your heart.
史莱德大师
Hey, Mr. Shredder.
我们是你的忠实粉丝 尤其喜欢你的早期作品
Big fan of your work. Especially your early stuff.
我的名字叫比博 这位是罗斯泰迪
My name is Bebop. This is Rocksteady.
这名字很奇怪是吧 他的祖先是从芬兰来的
I know it's a crazy name, right, but his ancestors are from Finland.
对 没错 我是芬兰人
Yeah, that's right. I'm Finnish.
所以我打人的时候 一定要干翻了他
Because when I start a beatdown, I always "finish" it!
- 什么 - 对 我说过了
- What? Did you hear that? - Yeah, I said it!
- 你听到了吗 - 老伙计
- I said it! - My man!
- 老伙计 - 抬起那只脚
- My man! - Give me that foot.
好
Yeah!
给我安静点儿
Hey! Shut up back there.
真是世事难料 对吧 史莱德
World works in mysterious ways, don't it, Shredder?
现在你只能跟这两个疯疯傻傻的家伙
Now you get to spend the rest of your life behind bars
一起度过后半生了
with these two knuckleheads.
那倒未必
Or not.
当心那些摩托
Hey. Check those bikes.
他们从两侧上来了
Coming up on our right and our left.
加速 快点儿伙计 快快快
Pin it! Pin it! Come on, man, go, go, go!
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
- 快叫支援 - 紧急呼叫
- Get us some help! - 10-13. 10-13.
我们遭到攻击 沿87号高速向北
We are being ambushed, heading north on 87.
需要紧急支援
We need immediate backup!
确保门已经锁死了
Make sure that gate is bolted.
散弹枪
Shotgun!
- 怎么没子弹 - 子弹在包里
- Where are the shells? - They're in the bag.
为什么把子弹放在该死的包里
What the hell are they doing in the bag?
棚顶上着火了
The roof is on fire!
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
就这样 上了高速
You send us on a highway
押送地球上最危险的罪犯
with the most dangerous criminal on the planet,
居然不把子弹上膛
and you don't load the shotgun!
他们上了囚车顶上
We got bogies on the bus.
- 把他们打下来 - 好的 按按钮
- Let's light them up. - Okay. Hit the button.
按钮 哪个按钮 这儿有无数个按钮
What button? What button? There are a million buttons.
- 3号按钮 - 3号
- Number three. Number three. - Three, three, three.
他们上来了 麦奇 清理右侧敌人
We got company. Mikey, clear our right flank.
尝尝我的大号双节棍吧
Nunchuks giganticus.
跟小朋友问个好
Say hello to my little friend.
干得好 麦奇
Good job, Mikey.
威力还真不小啊
Those things are pretty awesome, huh?
是啊 相当不小
Yeah, pretty awesome!
搞什么呢 快干掉那些乌龟
Get them out of there! Eliminate those turtles!
我讨厌那些家伙
I don't like those guys.
让我去好好教训这些混蛋 莱昂
I'm not being used to my full potential here, Leo.
别激动 拉斐尔 现在有点儿忙
Hey, just chill, Raph. We're a little busy.
伙计们 他们又回来了
Guys, they're coming back.
够了 是时候清理垃圾了
Enough! It's time to take out the trash.
好好学着点儿吧
That's how I roll.
让你开开眼界
That's how you roll.
还有什么需要我效劳的吗
Anything else I can do for you?
3号飞机 行动 把他带到预定地点
Raider 3, move in. Move in. Get him to the extraction point.
离14号出口还有2英里 马上准备拦截
We are two miles from Exit 14. Set up an intercept.
- 那是什么东西 - 是块特大号的磁铁
- What is that thing? - It's a big-ass magnet.
我有恐高症
Now we're talking!
到后面去 别让他们跑了
Get back there. Secure the prisoners.
站住
Shredder!
该死
Shit!
- 该死 那家伙要跑 - 他跑不了的
- He's getting away! - No, he's not.
耶
Yeah!
如果史莱德大师无法到达预定地点
If Sensei Shredder can't make it to the extraction point,
那就改变动手的地方
then we bring the extraction point to him.
- 快点 快点 - 别催我 见鬼
- Come on, come on, come on. - Don't rush me! Don't rush me!
耶
Yeah!
我的名字叫比博
Hey. My name is Be-bop!
嗨
Hi.
好吧 看你的了 麦奇
Okay. It's all you, Mikey.
瞧好吧
Time to shine.
不好意思
I'm sorry!
- 扳不动 - 见鬼
- It's stuck. - This sucks.
- 不是那个是这个 - 耶
- There it is. - Yeah!
看我的威力吧
This is awesome!
得提前启动传送程序了
We have to teleport Shredder earlier.
但是你说
But you said...
没错 这样做对史莱德来说非常危险
Yes, that that would be irresponsibly dangerous. True.
好了 多尼 让麦奇尽量靠近些
All right, Donnie, you've got to get Mikey closer.
锁定目标
Locking on.
你只有一次机会
One shot is all you got.
开始传送
Initiate.
快开炮 麦奇
Take the shot, Mikey!
跑哪儿去了
Where'd he go?
成功了
It worked!
什么 不知道传送到哪儿去了
But... Shredder's location unknown?
这是哪儿
Where am I?
这很重要吗
Does it matter?
我知道你现在心里在想什么
I know what you're thinking right now.
你在想用什么办法杀掉我
Of all the ways you'd like to kill me.
但那需要你比我脑袋转的快
But that would require you outthinking me.
很可惜 没有人能比朗格还聪明
And no one, no thing is smarter than the Krang!
真是抱歉
I'm sorry.
是不是不小心我的触须碰到你眼睛了 史莱德
Did I get a little tentacle mucus in your eyes, Shredder?
你知道我的名字
So you know my name.
我为什么会在这里
Why am I here?
因为你和你的伙伴 斯多克曼博士
Because you and your buddy Dr. Stockman
发现了我的东西
found something of mine.
就是心灵传送装置
The teleportation device.
我们要用它来帮助我逃脱警方的控制
The teleport was supposed to break me out of prison.
它能做的事可远不止这些
But it is capable of so much more.
实际上它是我的时空传送器上的一部分
That device is part of a machine called the arc capacitor.
几年前 我把时空传送器发射到地球时空
Years ago, I launched the arc capacitor to Earth's dimension.
可是 在进入地球大气层的时候巨大的阻力使它分解成了三部分
But upon entering your atmosphere, it broke apart into three pieces.
你和巴克斯特得到的是一部分
You and Stockman have one piece.
另一部分在纽约博物馆里
Another is in a museum in New York.
还有一部分落在了巴西的热带雨林
The third is in the Brazilian rainforest.
找到另外两部分装置
Collect the other two pieces.
斯多克曼博士就有足够的能力
Dr. Stockman should be inventive enough
重新组装出时空传送器
to reassemble the arc capacitor.
那又能怎么样
And then what?
能打开时空入口 我的战争机器科技堡垒
It will open a portal through which I can bring my war machine,
就能畅通无阻地来到地球
the Technodrome, to Earth.
我们可以携手让地球上的人对你俯首称臣
Together, we can bring the people of your planet to their knees.
我很感兴趣
I'm interested.
我可以协助你征服这个星球 但前提是你要帮我解决掉一个难题
I will help you take down planet Earth if you help me with my problem.
有四个混小子会来阻止我
Four brothers will try to stop me.
忍者龟
Turtles.
我知道你们之间的恩怨
I'm aware of your past.
给你这个
Take this.
它能解决你跟那些家伙之间的所有问题
It will solve all your problems with those pests.
我等着在地球跟你见面
I'll see you on the other side.
把我塞回去呀
Push me back in!
用点儿力 你这笨手笨脚的机器人
Push me in, you stupid robot.
在来点
More!
简直笨死了
You idiot!
- 他就那么消失了 - 等等
- Okay, so he just vanished? - Wait, wait, wait.
我播放一下随身监控画面
If I run the video from my shoulder camera
尽管会有干扰
through an electrostatic filter,
也许会看到史莱德到底在搞什么鬼
we might be able to see what happened to Shredder.
快 快点儿播放吧 兄弟
Come on. Show me something, buddy.
看 看那儿
Look! Right there!
看起来这家伙好像是进入心灵传送状态
It appears to be some kind of residue from a teleportation event.
对 通过心灵传送逃出升天了 情况不妙
Yeah, teleportation event residue, man. It's the worst.
难道真有心灵传送这种技术
Does that kind of technology even exist?
巴克斯特·斯多克曼研究这项技术很多年了
Baxter Stockman's been working on this kind of tech for years.
我从他的iPad上下载的邮件
All of that stuff that I pulled off of his iPad,
全部是关于史莱德和大脚帮的
it was full of information about Shredder and the Foot Clan.
所有行动计划都在里面
It was like a virtual playbook!
巴克斯特肯定还有备份 我敢打赌是在T.C.R.I的主机里
Baxter has to have a backup. And I bet it's on the mainframe at TCRI.
多尼 我需要装备 拿来吧
Donnie, I need something. What do you got?
等等
Wait.
我知道你要的是什么
I know exactly what you need.
绝对方便快捷
Totally plug-and-play.
太好了 我去盗取数据
Perfect. I'll go check it out.
我们也去 战术支援
We'll go with. Operate in support.
等等
Wait.
天已经亮了
The sun's coming up.
你们不能出去的 等着我
You can't go outside. You'll be seen.
臭名昭著的罪犯史莱德
The notorious criminal known as Shredder
昨晚在警方押送途中逃脱 下落不明
escaped police custody last night...
他在曼哈顿南部被判
He was being transported from Lower Manhattan
终身监禁
where he was serving a life sentence...
目前正在全国范围展开搜捕
There's a statewide manhunt in progress,
警方提醒大家
with the police chief saying
该犯穷凶极恶 请大家注意防范
he will stop at nothing to capture the fugitive.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
搜索半径扩大到200英里 注意桥梁和码头
Widen the search radius to 200 miles on all bridges and ports.
国土安全部和边境巡逻队的信息每小时汇报一次
And I want hourly updates from Homeland Security and Border Patrol.
应该是半个小时一次
Make it on the half hour.
你是谁
Excuse me?
这案子现在我负责
This is my investigation now.
重案组警官文森特
Bureau Chief Vincent. Organized Crime.
我有司法管辖权
I have jurisdictional authority.
你已经失去了管辖权
You forfeited jurisdiction.
一夜之间让三个重刑犯逃脱羁押
And you proved to be an authority on nothing
你已经涉嫌严重读职
when you lost three convicted felons in one night!
史莱德是这个城市有史以来最凶恶的罪犯
Shredder's the most notorious criminal this city has ever seen.
我们抓住了他
And we had him!
却被你放跑了
Now he's out there.
你这辆牢不可破的囚车是从哪儿找回来的
And where did you recover this highly secured vehicle?
在乔治华盛顿大桥下面找到的 被洗劫一空了
Found it under the G.W. Bridge, abandoned and stripped.
有目击证人吗
Any witnesses?
很遗憾没有
Unfortunately.
一切都是按规定程序来的
Everything's normal, I'm following procedure,
可是随后发生的事情太离奇了 忍者骑着摩托
and the next thing I know, ninjas on motorcycles just...
飞快地追了上来
They come zipping past!
他们从各个方向对我们不停地攻击
And they're coming at us from every possible direction.
- 继续讲 - 好的
- Keep going. - Okay.
我从倒车镜里看到了 一辆很大的清洁车
I look at my side view and I see what has to be a giant garbage truck
正要对我们开炮 那感觉就好像是坦克大战一样
that is just barreling towards us like it is on a warpath.
你是说看见了一辆全副武装的垃圾清扫车吗
And what was the objective of this battle-hungry sanitation vehicle?
当时我也觉得非常奇怪
See, I'm wondering the same thing myself.
但是 紧接着从那辆车的鬼脸里
But then it starts launching manhole covers
不停地发射下水井盖
right from the grille of the truck.
发射井盖
Manhole covers!
对 是下水井盖 而且打的特别准
Yeah, manhole covers. As guided projectiles.
你该去看医生了 琼斯 批准你不带薪休假
You're taking some time off, Jones. I'm pulling you off the payroll.
我没胡说八道 这都是真的
Hey, I'm not crazy! I know what I saw!
听着 我能帮你们抓到那些家伙
Look, I can help you catch these guys.
我是纽约人 那地方我比谁都熟悉
I'm from New York. I know these streets better than anyone.
逃犯追踪第一条守则
First rule of tracking fugitives:
不要接受最初导致
Don't take help from someone
罪犯逃脱者的任何帮助
who's responsible for losing them in the first place.
我们是被袭击的
We were ambushed!
- 感谢你的讲述 琼斯 - 请叫我琼斯警官
- Thanks for your statement, Jones. - That's Officer Jones!
早晚有一天我会成为警探
And I'm gonna be a detective someday.
等警校下一届招生我就去报名
I'm just waiting for the next round of applications at the academy.
那祝你好运
Good luck with that.
不过目前还是该明智点儿
As for now, do yourself a favor.
追捕逃犯是专业人士的事儿
Leave this manhunt to the professionals.
(名字 欧文·罗斯泰迪 普用名)
(常去处所 马蹄铁酒吧)
这两个混蛋居然还喜欢泡吧
So you two idiots have a favorite bar.
他们不会蠢到跑回酒吧去吧
Yeah, they're not gonna be stupid enough to go back there.
肯定在那儿
Yeah, they are.
伙计 那个倒霉的司机脑袋还真挺硬的
Man, I really rattled that prison guard's noggin good.
看见他摔的那样儿了吗
Did you see that head butt connect?
听见了吗 我可是听见了 感觉真是太爽了
See it? I felt it, I heard it, echoing off the walls!
- 老伙计 - 老伙计
- My man! - My man!
跟我妈妈做的味道一样
Just like Mama used to make.
老板 我的三明治呢
Oi, barkeep! Where are those sammies?
好的 来了 两位慢用
Here you go, guys. House special.
是够慢的
It's about time.
还有小咸菜
And a side of pickles.
小咸菜能防追踪吗
And are these pickles untraceable?
连史莱德本人都很难追踪 老伙计
Those phones are harder to track than Shredder himself, homeboy.
最好别跟我们贼眉鼠眼的 明白吗
Hey, do not make eye contact with us.
拿我们当乡巴佬呢
He think we somethin' to play with.
听着比博
You know, Beebs,
我是真不想再给别人当小弟了
I'm tired of being someone else's errand boy.
史莱德消失了 对我们却是个机会
With Shredder out of the picture, maybe we could step up.
可以拥有我们自己的地盘
Carve out our own piece of the city.
对
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
也许还有我们自己的帮派
Maybe even start our own Foot Clan.
我觉得我们的帮派最好就叫大腿帮
Eventually work our way up to our own Leg Clan!
说实话 这不是什么难事儿
I mean, honestly, how hard could it be?
嗨
Hey!
史莱德先生 老伙计
Mr. Shredder! My man.
真是太巧了 我们俩正在探讨
Coincidentally, we were just contemplating a consolidation
怎么才能让我们的犯罪王国更加强大
of our criminal enterprises.
比如按51%和49%的比例分成
We were thinking like a 51/49 split.
当然是你们占大头
Leaning your way, of course.
他不是来找搭档的
He's not looking for partners.
我是来找人卖命的
I'm looking for errand boys.
我们绝对能胜任
Well, we could work with that.
感觉怎么样
Wassup, drone?
没吓到你吧
I ain't scared of you.
像蝴蝶一样轻灵 具有蜜蜂的攻击性
Float like a butterfly, sting like a bee.
每次我们回到这里
Every second we're down here,
史莱德都实力大增 麦奇却越来越闹人
Shredder gets more powerful and Mikey gets more annoying.
我听见了
Hey, I heard that!
我们在训练
We're training.
算是吧
Sort of.
只要太阳一落山 就是我们的时刻了
As soon as the sun goes down, it's turtle time.
伙计 在跟我说话
Hi, drone. You talking to me?
我可没看见有别人
Because I don't see anybody else...
对不起 斯普林特师傅
I failed, Master Splinter.
你相信我 可我却让史莱德给溜了
You put me in charge, and Shredder slipped through our fingers.
你们根本没有办法阻止他
There's nothing you could have done to stop it.
不用因为挫折而一撅不振
Do not let this setback distract you.
要记住
Remember,
只要你还是他们几个的领头人 就永远不要轻言放弃
as long as you keep the team unified, you shall always succeed.
警方希望知道逃犯下落的人
We're asking anyone with information about the fugitives' whereabouts,
及时将情况反映给当局
to please pass it along to authorities...
我再问你一遍
I just want to ask you one more time.
你确定他们没来过这儿
Are you sure those guys didn't come through here?
朋友 我不知道你在说什么
Hey, pal, I don't know what you're talking about.
好吧
Okay.
知道吗 我喜欢这首歌
You know what? I love this song!
我拿回去听你不介意吧
You don't mind if I borrow this, do you?
你在干什么
Hey... What are you doing?
还真是不好意思
Nah, you know what? Never mind.
- 这CD划伤了 - 真见鬼
- It has a scratch on it. - Damn it!
或者再喝杯酒
Or maybe I'll have a drink.
- 你是不是疯了 - 差不多吧
- Are you out of your mind? - Getting there.
哎
Hey!
住手 别砸了 别砸了好吗
Stop it! Stop it! Just stop it, okay?
想告诉我了是吗
You ready to tell me where they are?
我卖给他们一部手机 就是这些了
I slipped them cell phones. That's all I know!
我想作为一个负责任的商人比如说你
And I imagine a responsible businessperson such as yourself,
不可能只卖硬件丝毫不关心如何去追踪吧 那不现实
wouldn't sell hardware without a means by which to track said hardware.
- 我说的对吗 - 行了 给
- Am I right? - Look! Here.
我有GPS 行了吧 可以找到他们
I have a GPS, okay? You'll find them with that.
你现在在哪儿
Where are you?
系统把你传送到哪儿去了
Where did it spit you out?
史莱德大师
Sensei Shredder.
逃脱计划成功了
The escape plan, it worked!
但跟你设计的不一样
But not in the way you planned.
我被传送到了很远的地方
I've traveled very far, and now...
我们有事情要做
We have work to do.
呼叫耐斯特德 请回答
Neustedder, come in.
呼叫耐斯特德
Neustedder?
呼叫耐斯特德 请回答
Neustedder, do you copy?
发现它的时候
When I found this thing,
我还真没想到它还能有这么大的用处
I never could have imagined its significance.
不过那个朗格指挥官真的说
But this Commander Krang,
它能打开通往另一个时空的大门
he said that this will help open a portal to another dimension?
一旦成功 我们将跟他一起统治这个星球
And when we do, we'll join him in dominating this planet.
- 我们将拥有无边的权力 - 权力
- We'll have ultimate power. - Power.
真是不敢想象
And indescribable glory.
我们将打开连接两个世界的时空之门
To be responsible for opening the fabric between two worlds!
这简直
It's...
要打开时空之门 必须找到另外一部分装置
There are other pieces required to open the portal.
为了防止那四个家伙来捣乱
If those four brothers are still out there,
我们需要武力值更高的战士来对付他们
we need to create soldiers that can defeat them with a single blow.
有了它一切就不在话下了
And this will help us do that.
需要先进行合成
It needs to be synthesized.
这个任务就交给你了
Which is where you come in.
快给天才让路
Here come the brains.
罗克 你看你这个
Yo, Rock, check this out.
比博 改天我也弄个实验室玩玩
Beebs, I got to get meseif one of these.
那该多有意思啊
Think of what we could do with this!
好像又回到了科学课上
I feel like I'm back in science class.
现在只需要找
Now all we need
实验目标了
are test subjects.
实验对象将对我的指令无条件服从
Candidates that will easily fall under my command.
四肢很发达
Large in size.
头脑却很简单
Low in intellect.
这玩意儿
That stings!
不太舒服
And not in a good way.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我们这到底是怎么了
What is happening to us?
不知道 不过这感觉很爽
I don't know, but this feels great!
这下可有意思了
This is gonna be good!
感觉很奇怪啊
This feels funny.
好像吃了摇头丸一样
Feels like I have ants in my pants.
摇屁股
Big ants!
好了 比博和罗斯泰迪
All right, Bebop and Rocksteady,
我知道你们就在大楼里
I know you're up there somewhere.
我知道
I knew it!
奥姆尼丝 扫描实验对象
Omnus, scan subjects.
扫描中
Searching.
这太神奇了
Miraculous.
每个人的体内 都有一组潜伏的基因
Inside every human there's a dormant gene
控制我们不会出现返祖现象
which ties us to our animal ancestors.
看起来这紫色的药液让他们重新
It's as if that purple ooze has returned them to their rightful place
在野兽王国找到了位置
in the animal kingdom.
罗克
Rock!
你变成了一只牛头怪
You're a rhinoceros.
你是个
And you're a...
说不上是什么东西
I don't know what you are.
好吧 我看看
All right, let me look, let me look. I'm a...
我是一只小猪
I'm a little piggy.
确切说是疣猪
You're a warthog.
- 比博 - 干什么 罗克
- Hey, Beebs! - Yeah, Rock.
让你看看犀牛的厉害
Ever see a rhino charge?
好疼啊
That hurts.
- 感觉真爽 - 我也是
- I like it! - Me, too!
我也是
Me, too.
准备好所有的容器
Prepare the entire container.
这样的战士越多 打开时空之门的把握就越大
The more of them we create, the easier it will be to secure the portal.
老伙计
My man!
真是太好了
This is awesome!
看看我的牛角
Check out the horn!
是啊 没错
Yeah, baby!
伙计 看看我的尾巴 看 还会动呢
Hey, man, check out my tail. Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle.
太酷了 我有吗
That is cool. Do I have one?
我 罗克 那是谁
Hey, Rock, who is that?
奥尼尔
O'Neil.
把药液给我抢回来
Get that canister!
你们不是真的想要重蹈覆辙吧
You guys don't really want to do this again, right?
好像结局一直都是你们灰溜溜的
It doesn't usually work out well for you guys.
因为我还有四个帮手
Because I have the four friends.
他们可是忍者
They're green ninjas.
把东西交出来
Give us the ooze.
哪儿去了
Where'd it go?
- 站住 - 不许动
- Stop! - Freeze!
东西在那小子的手里 被他给拿走了
See, that guy with the hockey stick in the other alley,
我跟这事儿没关系
I have nothing to do with that.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 你叫什么 - 凯西·琼斯
- What's your name? - Casey Jones.
- 什么 - 凯西·琼斯
- What's that? - Casey Jones.
该死不死
Stacy Moans?
凯西·琼斯
Casey Jones.
嗨
Hi.
- 离她远点儿 - 嘿
- Get away from her! - Hey!
躲后面 别过来
Get back. Get back.
不要吃我们
Do not eat us.
我们不是食物
We are not food.
地球人不是你们的敌人
The people of Earth are not your enemies.
明白
Yeah? Yeah.
看看这个
Watch this.
我们是至高无上的君主派来的
We were sent by the Supreme Leader
来吃美味的地球人
to eat delicious humans
吃不了的都拌上沙拉酱
and dip them in ranch dressing.
开玩笑的
I'm just kidding.
我吃素的 除了肉 奶酪 还有鸡蛋
I'm a vegan. Except for meat and cheese and eggs.
凯西 他们是我朋友
Casey, they're my friends.
他们
They...
他们是你朋友
They're your friends.
对 是我朋友
Yeah, they're my friends.
- 你来说 - 好
- Tell him. - Yeah.
戴着紫色眼罩的那个是技术天才多纳泰罗
Donatello over there in the purple, he's a technical genius,
技术男
who is technically a genius!
大帅哥 拉斐尔的眼罩是红的 像个可爱的大号泰迪熊
Raphael over there in the red, he's like a big cuddly teddy bear,
只可惜这个大号泰迪熊脾气有点儿爆
if big cuddly teddy bears were incredibly violent.
这位是莱昂纳多 他是蓝色的 勇敢的领袖
This is Leonardo. He's in the blue. Fearless leader.
悄然无声 杀人无形
Silent but deadly.
我是米开朗基罗 很喜欢我的橙色
And I'm Michelangelo, sporting my signature orange.
我的优点很多 聪明 强壮 个人魅力也相当不错
I'm a triple threat... Brains, brawn, and obviously a dazzling personality.
- 女士们都叫我麦奇 - 说完了吗
- Ladies like to call me Mikey. - Are you done?
是的
Yeah.
抱歉 来晚了 爱普尔
Sorry we're late, April.
你不想说一说事情的原委吗
You want to walk me through what's going on here?
好的 我一直在盯着巴克斯特 后来发现了史莱德
Okay, so I went to go see Baxter, but then Shredder was there.
听他们说要打开什么大门
And then he was talking about opening up some sort of portal
好像说是通往另一个时空的
to another dimension, and then he...
然后他拿出了这个药液
He took this purple ooze
把它注射到了两个逃犯的身上 就是在他手中逃脱的那两个
and he injected it into those two criminals that escaped with him.
然后他们一个变成了犀牛
And then he turned one of them into a rhinoceros
而另外一个变成了疣猪
and the other one into a warthog.
你看到比博和罗斯泰迪了
You have eyes on Bebop and Rocksteady?
为什么这么关心他们
Why do you care about those two?
如果能把他们捉拿归案
Let's just say that I have a vested interest
对我来说意义重大
in bringing them to justice.
我们回大本营
Let's get back to the lair.
拉斐尔 你跟这位黑色星期五在这儿盯着
Raph, grab Friday the 13th here and follow.
如果能帮我们找到比博和罗斯泰迪就让他加入
If he can help us find Bebop and Rocksteady, he's coming with.
不 这根本不可能 我哪儿也不想去
No, he's not. Not a chance. I'm staying right here.
我很理解你 可惜你错了
I'd agree with you, but you're wrong.
是我们俩一起分享这个任务
See, we, too, share a "vested interest."
我不会跟你们分享任何事情的
I don't share anything with you guys.
伙计们
Fellas, fellas...
纽约人民需要我们
Now, the people of New York
暂时抛开彼此之间的分歧 求同存异
need us to set aside our differences and work together.
眼前的问题只有一个
Which begs only one question.
你们两个之间到底是什么关系
Are you two guys like a thing or...
行了 走吧
Come on, move it!
如果这种药液被注射进了比博和罗斯泰迪的体内
If this purple ooze was injected into Bebop and Rocksteady's bloodstream,
那就有可能通过同位素的唯一性进行精确定位
it's feasible that were I to pinpoint a singular isotopic signature,
这样我们就可以追踪到他们的位置
I may be able to use it to track their location.
如果找到他们 就能找到史莱德
And if we find them, then we find Shredder.
把他们全送回监狱
Put them all in shackles!
你说戴着冰球面具去抓他们
And as long as we all have our hockey masks,
别开玩笑了
what could go wrong?
开玩笑 我居然跑到这儿来
Seriously? Now I'm taking wardrobe advice
跟一群怪物谈合作
from a bunch of Swamp Things...
一群生活在地下儿童乐园
Hey! Living in an underground amusement park,
不好意思 名字还都那么自命不凡
and have, forgive me, the most pretentious names ever.
不好意思 名字是我起的
Excuse me, I named them.
伙计们
Hey, guys?
动出声 别动
Nobody move. Don't move!
有一只好大的老鼠在那边
There is a giant rat back there.
是啊 我们以前也见到过
Yeah, we've seen him around here before.
要想干掉他只有一个办法
You know, there's only one way to get rid of him.
- 放低身姿 - 再低 对
- You got to get low. - Low! Yeah.
冲向他的时候速度一定要快 才能更有力
When you go at him, you got to go fast, and you got to go hard.
我们相信你 凯西·琼斯 看你的了
We believe in you, Casey Jones. It's all you, bro.
肯定没问题的 你绝对能行
Exactly. We need you to get him.
三 二 一 上
Three, two, one, go!
大老鼠一分 新来的零分
Giant rat, 1. Newguy, 0.
没想到他这么好骗
I can't believe it was that easy.
还以为不会那么轻易上当呢
I almost thought he wasn't gonna do it for a second.
不错 真不错
Good stuff. Good stuff.
以后可以多找些人来玩
We should really have people over more often.
你是要走吗
You're leaving?
我还是出去自己想办法吧
If I can find my way out of here, I am.
我本来干得好好的 一直在追踪他们
You know, I was doing just fine tracking Bebop and Rocksteady,
可是突然被你们横插了一杠子
and then you just T-boned my existence.
我一定要找到他们 找不到我誓不罢休
So now I'm gonna find them or I'm gonna go down swinging.
- 凯西 - 老话说的好
- Casey... - No, it's like they say,
想要成功 别待在动物园里
"If you want to get work done, don't spend time at the zoo."
神龟兄弟
"Tartaruga Brothers"?
这是那
That's the...
就是那辆车
That's the truck.
是他们
It was them.
他们到底是什么人
Who are these guys?
他们四个为这座城市所付出的你远远不知道
These four have done more for this city than you will ever know
他们也从不在意舆论的评价
or they will ever take credit for.
所以如果你真想追查到底
So if you want to go down swinging,
他们是最好的合作对象
these guys hit harder than anyone.
好了 多尼 你会成功的
All right, Donnie, you got this.
好的
Okay.
溶解四联螺旋基因链 反向作用聚合力
Dissolve the quadra-helix bonds and reverse the cohesion.
等等
Wait.
这意味着
That would mean...
这真的可能吗
Is it really possible?
已经得到确认 史莱德大师
We have confirmation, Master Shredder.
那瓶药液就存放在警察总部
The canister of purple ooze is at police headquarters.
不惜代价 马上派人抢回来
Take a team. Recover it at all costs.
我要去寻找时空传送器的第一部分
I'll retrieve the first piece needed to open the portal.
需要用多少人
How many men do you want?
这个任务交给普通人我不放心
This job is too important for just men.
就交给那两个头脑简单四肢发达的蠢货去做吧
I'm bringing with me the next generation of finely tuned combat soldiers.
你跟我说实话 罗克
Hey, I've been meaning to ask you this, Rock.
我是不是看起来很胖
Do 1100k fat to you?
胖 不 伙计 不
Fat? No, buddy, no.
你那是
You look
相当胖
really fat!
肚子一定要大 才能吃遍天下
The belly must be jelly, because jam don't shake like that.
- 老伙计 - 老伙计
- My man! - My man!
天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
莱昂
Leo. Leo! Leo!
Leo!
莱昂 我的天哪 不可思议
Leo! My gosh. My gosh. This is amazing!
莱昂 你肯定不会相信
Leo, Leo, okay. You're not gonna believe this.
你知道我从紫色药液中取出了一部分样本
Okay, I made a solution from a sample of the purple ooze,
好加快完成同位素的分析研究
right, to expedite analysis of the isotope?
可是在等待催化反应的时候我就在想
But while I was waiting for it to catalyze, I started thinking,
既然这药液能把人变成动物
if the purple ooze can turn humans into animals,
那也许就能够实现反向进程
perhaps if properly reengineered...
看这个
Watch this. Watch this.
它能把我们变成
It could turn us
人类
into humans.
如果我们能弄到足够的药液
If we could get our hands on more of this stuff,
就能改变我们的命运
it could be life changing!
我们不需要这样的变化
We don't need that kind of change.
好吧 也对
Okay. You're right.
跟人类在一起会让我们失去现有的优势
To blend in with humans could compromise our strategic advantage.
我们有行之有效的系统
We have a system that works.
不应该打乱这一切
We shouldn't mess with the formula.
还有 多尼
And, Donnie.
听着
Listen.
不能跟别人透露一个字
You can't say a word of this to the others.
(美国自然历史博物馆)
看看这个地方
Look at this place.
再想一想整个宇宙
And to think, the entire universe,
一切都是从大爆炸开始的
it all started with the Big Bang.
是吗 比博 那我也来个大爆炸
Yeah, Beebs? Well, I got a "Big Bang" for you.
伙计 实在太臭了 简直都喘不过气了
Man! That is awful! That is the worst!
- 把它撞开 - 小菜一碟
- Smash it. - That's what we do!
这石头太硬了
That rock is hard.
- 我腿都麻了 - 我头都晕了 伙计
- Can't feel my legs. - Twisted my melon, man.
现在只差最后一部分了
Only one piece left to recover.
准备出趟远门吧 小伙子们
Get ready to take a trip, boys.
到巴西去转一转
You're going to Brazil.
我连泳裤都准备好了
My Speedo's already packed!
我开始还不信
I didn't believe it,
可是多尼跟他展示了的确有效
but then Donnie showed him it could really work.
这东西的吸引力太大了
It was the coolest thing I've ever seen.
给了你希望
It gave me hope.
也许我们不用永远困在这里了 对吗
Maybe we don't have to be stuck down here forever, you know.
莱昂跟多尼说要对我们保密
So Leo told Donnie to keep it a secret.
对我们
From us?
- 不 - 他以为他是谁
- No. Hold on. - Who does he think he is?
不 等等 听我说 如果你告诉莱昂是我告诉你 多尼告诉他
No, wait. Hey, look, if you tell Leo that I told you that Donnie told him...
那我们的圣诞节嘻哈唱片 就彻底泡汤了
We'll never finish our hip-hop Christmas album!
突击问答
Pop quiz.
忍者最重要的三个特征是什么
What are the three most important traits of the ninja?
速度
Speed.
隐匿
Stealth.
还有忠诚
And honor.
兄弟之间藏着掖着是忠诚吗
Where's the honor in keeping secrets from your brothers?
不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
现在你又加上了一条说谎
So now you're adding lying to the list.
如果你是指多尼告诉我的药液的事儿
If you're referring to what Donnie told me about the purple ooze,
那是特殊情况需要特殊处理
it's called "compartmentalization of information."
那对我们来说是变成人类的机会
If there's even a chance that ooze can make us human...
我们是乌龟 你喜不喜欢都是
We're turtles, whether you like it or not.
这不在于我喜不喜欢
It's not about what I like,
问题是有多少人能接受我们这个样子
it's about what people up there are willing to accept.
真正的接受是由内而外的
True acceptance only comes from within.
别跟我说这种虚伪的大道理
Don't give me that fortune cookie muck!
你在做这种决定之前应该先跟我们商量一下
You should consult with us before you decide to do something like that!
我跟多尼商量了 我们决定
I consulted Donnie. And we decided...
那麦奇呢 他弃权了吗
And what about Mikey? He don't get a vote?
在这个家庭里只有一个人有决定权
There's only one vote that counts in this family!
就是我
Mine!
莱昂
Leo.
莱昂 刚才在海登天文馆有警报触发
Leo, an alarm just tripped at the Hayden Planetarium.
我们得马上过去
We have to get uptown.
带上装备 多尼
Gear up, Donnie.
你俩留在这儿
You two stay here.
你是在报复我
You're benching me?
- 随便你怎么想 - 关我什么事
- Call it what you want. - What'd I do?
抱歉 伙计们
Sorry, guys.
莫名其妙
Well, that went well.
简直太不像话了 明显是欺负人
The nerve this guy has. Big timing us!
也许他觉得现在这样挺好
He may be fine with the status quo,
可并不意味着 我们就不能有自己的想法
but that don't mean we can't make our own decisions.
就是
Yeah!
等等 你在说什么
Wait. Wait. What are you saying?
就是说还有更多那种紫色的药液
It means there's more where that purple ooze came from.
你和我都能拥有一份
And we're gonna get our hands on it.
耶
Yeah!
我还是没明白你的意思
I still don't know what you're saying.
我们现在做什么
Are we... Are we doing something?
美国自然历史博物馆
The American Museum of Natural History.
我一直想来这儿看看
I've always wanted to come here.
赶快四处查看 多尼
Quit screwing around, Donnie.
30秒后警察就会到达正门
Thirty seconds till the cops are at the door.
多尼
Donnie...
史莱德和那两个怪物肯定在这儿
Shredder and the mutants were definitely here.
我正在检测0号元素的痕迹
And I'm detecting traces of neutronium,
这是建立可控性黑洞必不可少的关键性物质
the critical ingredient required for creating a controlled black hole.
而且 黑洞是宇宙中唯一有能力切断时空连续性的
Which is the only thing capable of rupturing the space-time continuum.
知道这意味着什么吗
And you know what that means!
不 不知道 多尼
No. I don't, Donnie.
这意味着史莱德并不像我想的是个疯子
It means Shredder may not be as nuts as I thought.
从刚才收集的数据看
From the data I just collected,
我推测在我们眼前的这个东西的里面
I'm surmising that what was inside this thing
应该有能帮他打开时空之门的东西
may help Shredder open that portal to another dimension.
好吧 我想知道的是
Okay, what I want to know is,
如果时空之门被打开
if a portal's gonna open up,
从另一个时空过来的会是什么
what's coming through from the other side?
你的意思是我们要闯进警察总部
So you want to break into police headquarters.
对
Yeah.
多尼说需要更多的药液
Donnie said he needs more of the purple ooze
来追踪比博和罗斯泰迪
to track Bebop and Rocksteady.
你说过药液现在应该被警方
And you said the cops would've logged it
存放在证物保管室
into Evidence Control Room by now.
好吧 莱昂知道这个计划吗
Okay, and Leo is good with this plan?
这个行动是由我负责的
Actually, I'm in charge on this one.
- 是这样吧 麦奇 - 是这样
- Ain't that right, Mikey? - You're right.
看
Look.
这样我们能控制电梯和消防门
So, we can take the elevator shafts and vents.
你们两个只需要待在地上
We need you two to stay on the ground.
我不可能就这样大摇大摆地走进去
I can't just walk right into police headquarters.
- 你是胆小鬼吗 - 嘿
- What are you, chicken? - Hey!
你说谁是胆小鬼 小乌龟
Who are you calling chicken, turtle?
你到底想不想找到比博和罗斯泰迪
Look, do you want to find Bebop and Rocksteady or not?
那我们就去闯一闯警察总部
So we're breaking into police headquarters.
还有一个问题要商量
We got one last boondoggle.
我们需要一个人来掩护大家避开门卫的安全检查
We need to find someone to sneak you guys past security checkpoint.
唯一的办法是
Only plan I got so far
想办法让他们垂涎欲滴
may be a tad less than appetizing.
是去吃饭吗
Are we going somewhere?
是猎鹰 我会跟每个人都拍照的 别担心
I'm gonna take a photo with all of you, don't worry,
今晚大家都有机会
everybody's gonna get one tonight.
- 弗恩 欢迎你 偶像 - 怎么
- Hey, Vern. - Yeah?
粉丝 粉丝
Big fan. Big fan.
我的天哪 卡梅罗·安东尼 我可是你的粉丝
My gosh, Carmelo Anthony, right back at ya!
钥匙真漂亮
Nice key to the city.
谢谢你 这没什么大不了的
Thank you. Yeah, I mean, they give these things out.
梅罗 介意我叫你梅罗吗
Hey, Melo... Do you mind if I call you Melo?
当然不
Not at all.
听着 真高兴你把我叫了过来
Listen, I'm really glad that you stopped me, because,
你应该比我的感受还深
guys like you and me, we're kind of the same.
是啊
Right.
我们给人们的生活带来了欢乐和希望
We bring a lot of joy and hope into people's lives.
我们得到的是明星的光环
We got that kind of star power.
而作为回报 我们还应该
And while it's a gift, this bond that we have...
- 你在这儿呢 - 嘿
- There you are. - Hey.
梅罗 介绍一下 这是我女朋友 亚历桑德拉
Melo, I'd like to introduce you to my girlfriend, Alessandra.
女朋友 我们刚认识一周吧
Girlfriend? We just met a week ago.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
我们是一见钟情
Now we're all over each other. Stop it!
- 好了 别摸了 - 弗恩
- You know... - Vern!
其实我有个很好的建议
You know, what might be a great idea is if we...
弗恩
Vern!
- 我觉得我们应该 - 我们该走了
- I don't know... - We need to go.
还有别忘了带上你那把钥匙
And bring that key to the city with you.
- 我觉得你该走了 - 对
- I think you need to go. - Yep.
真不敢相信
Unbelievable, you know?
你的醋劲竟然会那么大
I mean, your jealousy knows no limits.
- 我们需要你的帮助 - 我们指谁
- We need your help. - We? Who's "we"?
这不是我们的城市英雄吗
Well, well, well, if it ain't the prince of the city.
行了 你歇歇吧 拉斐尔
You know what? Give me a break, Raph.
当初就是你非要让我出这个风头的
You're the one who told me to take credit for Shredder in the first place.
对 可现在却让那家伙跑了 无影无踪了
And now in light of the fact that he is who knows where,
我只不过是按照约定接受这些荣誉
I am starting to have profound regrets about our arrangement.
我们也可以换过来试一试
So, are we just gonna stand around and talk or...
- 这小子是谁 - 同是沦落人
- Who's this guy? - Total loser, bro.
我是说降落的落
I mean, nice enough fella,
像你这样的能举起哑铃就不错了
if you like guys who can't even bench press.
哔
Boom!
T恤有点儿肥呀
Or fill out a T-shirt.
弗恩 计划有他一份
Vern, he's a part of the plan.
到底是什么计划
What plan is that?
计划是闯进纽约警察总部
The plan to break into police headquarters.
- 什么 - 我们要找到史莱德
- What? - We need to find Shredder.
我们 不 不包括我
"We"? No, no, no. No, we're not doing...
听着 我很想帮你们 但是不行
Listen, I'd love to help you guys out, but I can't.
- 我要去听音乐会 - 钥匙不错
- I got concert tickets to a lunch. - Sweet key.
- 真能用来开门吗 - 不能 这只是象征性的
- Does it go to something? - No, it's just the city.
弗恩 作为这个由怪物组成的团体的新成员
Vern, as the resident new guy in this band of freaky misfits,
算我拜托你了 你就接受了吧
do yourself a favor, and just roll with it.
新来的 我早就接受了
Hey, new guy, all I do is roll with it.
我接受的时候
I've been rolling with it
你还穿开档裤呢
since you were wearing baby T-shirts because you were a baby.
警察总部 半小时后见
Police headquarters. Thirty minutes.
一会再见
See you there.
- 一会见 - 他说过了
- See you there. - He just said that.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
看谁来了 弗恩 猎鹰芬威克
Look who it is. Vern "The Falcon" Fenwick!
合个影吧 来吧
Let's take a picture, huh? Come on.
都过来 我来拍 然后发给你们
Yeah, I'll just take one and send it to all you guys. Just gotta...
就好像是全家福一样
do, like, a panorama thing there...
不错 非常好
You guys look good.
(扫描身份信息 查询权限)
- 能不能再快点儿 麦奇 - 我在快 在快
- Any time now, Mikey. - I'm hurrying, I'm hurrying.
(准许进入)
搞定
Yes!
好了 笑一笑 拍的帅一点儿
All right, smile. Smile for your...
(目标 锁定)
十分钟后开会
The meeting's in 10 minutes.
帮我把文件
I need to see...
卡哇邦嘎
Cowabunga.
麦奇 怎么样了
Hey, Mikey. What's up?
- 警报 - 出什么事了
- Mayday, mayday, mayday! - What's going on?
大脚帮抢走了药液
The Foot Clan have the purple ooze!
我们在警察总部急需马上支援
We need backup at police headquarters right now!
当心点儿 麦奇 马上到
Hang tight, Mikey. We'll be right there.
我们马上来
We're on the move.
我们得到上面的出口
We have to get above the exit!
你疯了吗 我们不能露面
What, are you crazy? We can't be seen!
药液是我们变成人类的唯一希望
That purple ooze is our only shot at being normal,
现在它就在我们面前
and it's heading toward the front door.
不许动
Freeze!
你跟不跟我来
You with me or not?
我们走
Let's go!
拉斐尔 你拿它干什么
Raph, what are you doing with that?
不许动
Freeze!
- 别动 - 不
- Don't move! Don't move! - No, no, no.
把手亮出来
Show me your hands!
别乱动
Freeze!
- 跪在地上 - 等等 我们是好人
- Get down on the ground. - Wait! We're the good guys!
- 跪在地上 - 好吧 好
- Get on the ground! - All right, okay.
你们的同伙呢
What are those things?
是群怪物
They're monsters.
是一群怪物
They're monsters!
我们不是怪物
We're not monsters.
不 别开枪
No! No! No! Don't shoot!
- 住手 - 别开枪
- Stop it! No, don't! - Don't shoot, don't shoot.
走 快走
Go now!
慢慢跪在地上 跪下
Get to the ground slowly. Get down!
琼斯 这玩笑可开大了
Jones, you've got to be kidding me.
把他们俩关起来
Put these two in holding.
婕德 我们刚才所看到的一切
Jade, what we just saw stays in the department.
对公众要严密封锁
The public doesn't need to know.
到处都是警方的监控器 他们在追捕你们
It is all over the police scanner, they are hunting you.
- 到底是怎么回事 - 你说吧 拉斐尔
- What happened up there? - Tell him, Raph.
告诉他你是怎么坏了规矩把我们暴露的
Tell him how you broke rank and got us all exposed.
还有那个极其自私的理由
For the most selfish reason.
大脚帮差点儿就抢走了药液
The Foot were gonna get their hands on it.
你还不明白吗
You didn't know that!
计划是侵入警察总部
Stealing from police headquarters...
可没有你被抓这一幕啊
There's no scenario where you wouldn't get caught.
也许你从来没跟家人撒过谎
Maybe if you hadn't lied to your own flesh and blood...
就像你对爱普尔撒谎那样
Wait. The way you lied to April?
现在因为你的胡来 她在受罚
And now she's taking the fall for your mess.
你没看到他们那种表情呢
You should've seen the looks on their faces.
那种惊恐的样子
They weren't just scared.
我实在
There was
不想再看到
actual hate.
一切都会好起来的 孩子
It will be all right, my son.
人类对未知的事物自然会感到恐惧
People fear what they do not understand.
你们不能就这样离开这儿
You can't walk away from this.
我说过他 斯普林特师傅
I told him, Master Splinter.
可是拉斐尔根本就一个字都听不进去
But Raph, he never hears a word I have to say.
现在他们都知道了关于药液的事情
Now, I knew they couldn't handle the truth about the purple ooze,
可结果呢 他们证明我没错
and you know what, they proved me right.
- 莱昂纳多 - 我没办法了
- Leonardo. - I don't know what to do!
多尼整天对着电脑 拉斐尔成天忙着健身
Donnie's nose is in his computer, Raph's brains are in his biceps,
麦奇呢 就会做白日梦
and Mikey's head's in the clouds!
我没办法让他们步调一致
I can't get them all on the same page.
做不到齐心协力
To think with one mind.
不一定非得要大家想的都一样
You shouldn't want them all to think the same.
只有各取所长才能让集体更加强大
It's their different points of view that make the team strong.
称职的领导 要学会理解
A good leader understands this.
称职的兄长 要懂得宽容
A good brother accepts it.
伙计们 我发现个情况
Guys? I got something!
说说吧 多尼
Talk to me, Donnie.
电脑利用药液中的同位素
The computer's pinpointed
精确地锁定了位置
the isotopic signature of the purple ooze.
我能找到比博和罗斯泰迪所在的坐标
I can track Bebop and Rocksteady's exact coordinates.
找到了
I got them.
在海拔三万六千英尺 移动速度是490节
They're at 36,000 feet, traveling at 490 knots.
这速度都能飞了
They've achieved the power of flight!
挺厉害呀 不是吗
Good for them, you know.
他们在飞机上 麦奇
They're on a plane, Mikey.
看来我们的两位变种朋友是要去巴西
It looks like our mutant buddies are headed to Brazil.
我们怎么去呢
How do we get there?
我们可以从肯尼迪机场混上货运飞机
We sneak onto the next cargo plane from JFK.
他们不是怪物 好么
They're not monsters, okay?
这城里真正的怪物是史莱德
The only real monster in this city is Shredder
和他弄出来的两个变种人
and the two mutants that he's created.
比博和罗斯泰迪
Bebop and Rocksteady.
如果你认为你所说的话
If you think anything coming out of your mouth
能为她增加一些可信度 那你就大错特错了
is gonna add to her credibility, you are sorely mistaken.
史莱德是在巴克斯特·斯多克曼的帮助下
Shredder mutated them with the help of Baxter Stockman.
使他们变异的 你真应该去看看
That's actually who you need to go see.
真有意思 既然你提到斯多克曼博士
Funny you should mention Dr. Stockman
我手里正好有一份
because we just finished analyzing
他交给我们的T.C.R.I.大厦监控画面 刚刚分析完
some security footage from TORI that he gave us.
- 很好 - 猜猜谁在里面
- Great. - Guess who's on it.
事实不是这样的
That's not what happened.
画面被改动过 重新编辑的
That footage has been altered. It's been edited.
我们检查过真实性
We checked its authenticity.
没改动过
It's clean.
我要打个电话
I want a phone call.
很遗憾地告诉你 因为那几个怪物闯入大厦
I hate to break it to you, but all the phones have been shut down
导致所有电话都不能使用了
on account of monsters breaking into our stationhouse.
我也遗憾地告诉你 按照法律规定 我有权打电话
Well, I hate to break it to you, but legally I'm entitled to a phone call.
- 告诉我他们在哪 - 不知道
- Tell me where they are. - l don't know.
就算知道我也不告诉你
But if I did, I wouldn't tell you.
组长
Oh chief,
那些乌龟不是你该关注的重点
the turtles are not the ones you should be chasing.
找到了
We found it!
快看啊
Look here.
我很喜欢
I like it.
老板 找到了
Boss, boss, we did it! We did it!
我们找到了那个硬家伙
We got that super-important-thingykind-of-hard-thing-to-find thing.
让开 把脸让开 老板看不到我了 老板
Move, move. Move your head over. He's got to see me. Hey, boss!
他们找到了最后一件 马上就回来了
They have the final piece and are heading back.
激动人心的时刻终于开始倒计时了
Countdown to the big show is officially on.
我们已经准备好了
And we are ready for action!
一切都已经准备就绪了
All systems are standing by.
你感觉到了吗 史莱德大师
Can you taste it, Sensei Shredder?
我们将要做的是多么伟大的事啊
The magnificence of what we're about to do?
难道不是吗
Yummy, isn't it?
难道就没有
Aren't there supposed to be, like,
比如空姐来送个热毛巾什么的服务吗
pretty stewardesses handing out warm hand towels and stuff?
那是商务舱 麦奇
Not down here, Mikey.
而不是这儿
Not for us.
伙计 比博和罗斯泰迪已经返程
Oh, boy. Bebop and Rocksteady are en route
- 回纽约了 - 什么
- back to New York. - What?
他们肯定已经找到
They must have already retrieved
打开时空之门所需要的东西了
the last piece they needed to open the portal.
好像能跟他们的飞机在空中相错
Looks like our plane's about to cross over theirs, right?
这儿 好 来个三万英尺高空行动
Yeah, with a 3,000-foot separation.
我可以控制拦截 但我们得跳伞
I could plot a course for intercept, but we'd have to jump.
跳伞
Jump?
天哪 伙计们
Oh, boy.
我可不知道是要这样跳下去
Guys, I don't know if this is such a good plan.
行了 别让我把你给看扁了
Come on, don't go getting soft on me now, Raph.
来吧 会很有意思的
This is gonna be fun.
马上行动吧 航线重叠最多只有30秒
We got to go now. We only have a 30-second window.
你应该知道的
You know the plan.
- 伙计 - 怎么了
- Dudes? - What?
他跳下去了
He jumped.
He jumped?
好吧 那就跳吧
All right, one for all.
等等 没背降落伞
Wait, wait, wait! You don't have a chute!
我不用降落伞 我有滑板
I don't need a chute. I got my board!
简直太刺激了
This is awesome!
跳偏了
I'm off.
- 偏了 我要掉下去了 - 想搭顺风车吗
- I'm off... I'm off target! - Need a lift, bro?
- 减速啊 麦奇 - 准备尖叫吧
- Slow down, Mikey! - Prepare for the ouch.
哦
Gotcha!
别放手 麦奇
Hang on, Mikey.
锁定
Lock in.
拉斐尔呢
Where's Raph?
好了 你能行的
Okay. Okay, you got this. You got this.
范·迪塞尔会怎么做
What would Vin Diesel do?
永不后悔 绝不恐惧
No regret, no fear.
No regret... No fear!
我既后悔又恐惧
I regret this! Fear sucks!
他是不是落得有点儿太快了
Isn't he coming in kind of fast?
拉斐尔
Raph!
身手不错嘛
Nice catch.
好消息是 你们有降落伞
The good news is you're wearing chutes.
降落伞
Chutes.
坏消息是
The bad news is...
好了 这一定是他们从巴西弄来的
Okay. This must be what they came to Brazil for.
这是打开时空之门需要的一部分东西
It's the interdimensional portal-opening thingy-ma-bob.
也许该给它起个好听点儿的名字 可是
Well, there's probably a more technical name for it, but...
伙计们
Guys?
天哪
Oh, boy.
伙计 你的发型不错啊
Dude! Bringing back the Mohawk!
跟你很配
Good for you.
你敢讽刺我
Y'all got jokes?
等我把你的脑袋砸烂 看你还怎么讽刺我
Well, let's see how funny you are after we bash your heads in!
当心
Watch it!
小心点儿
Careful!
天哪
Mommy!
伙计们 来吧
Guys!
伙计 你疯了
Dude! Seriously?
是我不对 我有点儿冲动了
Yep, that's my bad. I got a little carried away.
我得手了
I got it! I got it!
- 给我拿回来 - 我又失手了
- I'll take that. - I don't got it.
别担心 伙计们 我能控制住飞机
Don't worry, guys, I'll level out the plane!
还是一架敞篷的
And there's no cockpit.
当心 这里的东西随时都可能会移动
Careful, as some of the items may have shifted during flight.
你那边怎么样 多尼
How you doing up there, Donnie?
我这儿好极了 不能再好了
Everything is great. I'm doing awesome.
- 我是一只会飞的猪 - 莱昂
- This pig is flying! - Leo!
拉斐尔
Raph!
- 大家都没事吧 - 我没事
- Everyone okay? - I'm good.
我没事
I'm good!
等等 拉斐尔呢
Wait, where's Raph?
上岸了
Land!
Land! Land! Land!
让你见笑了
Well, this is awkward.
来比一下吧 宝贝儿
Let's rumble, baby!
拿到了
I got you, I got you.
- 莱昂 不 - 当心点儿 多尼
- Leo, no! - Eyes up, Donnie!
冲过去 来吧
Coming through!
拿到了
Gotcha!
I got it, I got it, I got it!
多尼
Donnie!
谢谢兄弟 老伙计
Thanks, buddy.
- 老伙计 - 老伙计
- My man. - My man!
再见了 小王八
Bye, turtles!
这么友好 还说声再见
That's nice of them to say good-bye.
- 当心了 - 说什么
- Heads up! - Wait, what?
谢谢 伙计们
Thanks, guys.
步调真一致
Real team effort.
你要是非认定我们有罪 那就随便吧
If you're gonna press charges, just press charges.
你还欠她一个电话
And you still owe her a phone call.
我不欠任何人任何事
I don't owe anybody anything
除非你告诉我那些乌龟是从哪儿来的
until you tell me where those turtle things came from.
新罕布什尔
From New Hampshire.
你比我想象的还不开窍
You're actually even a bigger loser than I thought.
别被她的话干扰了 她是想要激怒你
Don't worry about her, Casey. She's just trying to get under your skin.
不 她是对的
Nah, she's right.
不止一个人这么说我
Been hearing that my whole life.
其实我这辈子只有一个梦想
You know, I've only ever really had one goal.
我想要成为纽约警察局的一名探员
I wanted to make detective in the New York City Police Department.
我希望能扫除罪犯 不仅仅是在监狱里
I wanted to put criminals away, not just keep them in cages.
在惩教署工作这么久只学会了两件事
But working Corrections, you do learn two good things.
第一 审判不只有一种形式一个方式
One, justice comes in all shapes and sizes.
第二
And two,
偷东西远比你想象中的要容易的多
it's way easier to pick a cop's pocket than you might think.
打电话吧
Make your call.
(充气猎鹰)
- 嗯 - 弗恩
- Yeah? - Vern...
奥尼尔
O'NeiI!
弗恩 听着 我想要
Vern, listen, I need you to...
那是什么声音
What is that sound?
我搞了个小副业 猎鹰充气袋
Just a little side venture. Falcon breath.
我发现人们愿意花两百美元听个响
Turns out, people are willing to pay $200 a pop
买一口袋空气
for a bag of my hot air.
好吧 就当我没问过
Okay, look, forget that I asked.
凯西和我被关在警察局了
Casey and I are in police custody.
真震惊
Shocking!
难道他们想采访你
Why would they want to question you?
我是说是因为你闯入警察总部吗
I mean, just because you broke into their headquarters.
听着 现在有个问题比我的麻烦还大 明白吗
Vern, look, I've got bigger problems than myself right now, okay?
巴克斯特·斯多克曼篡改了T.C.R.I.的监控画面
Baxter Stockman doctored the footage from TCRI,
但是我相信肯定有个备用监控器
but I'm betting that there's some sort of a secondary feed
有完整的视频能证明他为史莱德工作
that will show that he's been working with Shredder
把比博和罗斯泰迪变成了变种人
and that they turned Bebop and Rocksteady into mutants.
可为什么要找我呢
Look... What do you want from me?
我希望你是个英雄 大家也都认为你是
I want you to be the hero that the whole city thinks you are.
- 请让一下 - 这里不对外开放
- Coming through. - It's a restricted area.
不开放
"Restricted"?
听着 我有个东西能打开这个城市的任何一扇门
You know, I know something that will open just about any door in this town.
城市钥匙
Key to the city.
你就是猎鹰
You are The Falcon?
你还没有资格大声说出我的名字
You haven't earned the respect yet to say my name out loud.
想要拥有这个资格吗
You want to put yourself on the path to that respect,
去楼下给我买杯摩卡奇诺吧
run downstairs and grab me a mochaccino.
备用监控器 到底会在哪儿呢
Secondary surveillance, where would you be?
拜托 弗恩
Come on, Vern...
成名之前你可是个职业摄像师呢
You were a cameraman before you got all fancy.
一个摄像头 两个摄像头 三个摄像头
One camera, two camera, three camera.
怎么没有第四个
Why isn't there a fourth...
隐蔽摄像头 在这儿呢
Hidden camera. Bingo!
时间刚刚好
Right on time.
你觉得袖手旁观 是一个英雄该做的事吗
You think standing on the sidelines makes you some kind of hero?
你怎么能那样从我身边硬挤过去呢
You can't just push past me like that, bro!
你以前是笨蛋 永远都是笨蛋
You were being a nitwit! You were gonna lose that thing!
我当时都抓住它了 可看你就好像我根本过不去一样
I had it right in my hand, and you acted like I wasn't even there!
我不可能随时都知道你们所在的位置
It's not my job to make your presence known, all right?
应该随时保持沟通
Get out of your head and communicate!
别指望他了 只讲技术不懂战术的家伙
Well, what do you expect? He's all logic, no skills!
一个不守纪律的人还有脸说这种话
Coming from the guy who's all instinct, no restraint!
我跟你说吧 兄弟
Dude, what do you know about anything?
这就叫有胆子没脑子 说什么呢
You're all heart and no brains.
就算你多懂了点儿战术
How could you? You may know a lot about strategy,
可是你懂感情吗
but you know nothing about feelings.
既然这样
Fair enough.
那我们就来说说感情
You want to know the one thing I am feeling?
我们是很好的兄弟
We may be brothers,
但缺乏团队精神
but we are not a team.
- 我们成功了 - 是的
- It's working! - Yes.
我们成功了
We did it.
一旦能量达到峰值 时空之门将会开到最大
Once it's fully powered, the portal will be just wide enough
科技堡垒就能源源不断地进来
for the Technodrome to come through piece by piece.
那场面将会多壮观
This is gonna be insane!
伽利略 埃塞克·牛顿
Galileo... Isaac Newton...
史蒂夫·乔布斯
Steve Jobs.
他们在科学史册上的位置
Their names will be footnotes in the annals of science
应该都比不上这里发生的一切
after what's about to happen here.
警官文森特
Chief Vincent.
我是弗恩·芬威克 也许你听说过
I'm Vern Fenwick. You might know me as The...
算了吧 听着
Doesn't matter. Listen.
你应该看看这个
You need to see this.
- 罗克 那是谁 - 奥尼尔
- Hey, Rock, who is that? - O'Neil.
快去抢回来
Get that canister!
放了他们
Let them go.
谢谢
Thank you,
猎鹰
"Falcon."
警官
Chief?
也许你需要这个
You might need this.
手法不错
Well played.
好极了 又多了个犀牛和疣猪 麻烦还真不少
Great. So I've got a rhino and a warthog to add to our troubles.
干得漂亮
Good looking out.
愿意效劳
Anytime.
全城警戒通缉巴克斯特·斯多克曼
I want an APB on a Dr. Baxter Stockman.
另外再
And get a few...
外面怎么回事 多尼
What's happening out there, Donnie?
我的天哪
My gosh.
史莱德成功了
Shredder did it.
时空之门打开了
The portal's opening.
- 那是什么 上帝 - 怎么回事
- Oh, my God! - What's going on?
那是从哪儿来的 上帝啊 太恐怖了
Where did that come from?
黑进他们的中央数据库
Hacking into the main data core.
好了 飞船的名字叫做
Okay. Ship's designate is
科技堡垒
the Technodrome.
对方指挥官的名字叫朗格
Commanding Officer goes by the name of Krang.
我不认识他 但我特别恨他
I don't know that guy, but I hate that guy!
如果他这飞船彻底完工
If Krang were to finish building this thing,
那就不仅仅是船了
it wouldn't just be a ship.
将是个战争机器 这里将生灵涂炭
It would be a war machine that would end all life here.
整个地球都无法幸免
It would be the end of the world.
但我们仍然有抗争的机会
But there is something we can do.
任何哺乳动物都是不可能
The atmosphere around the Technodrome would be toxic
在科技堡垒周围的大气层里 自由呼吸的
to anyone with a standard cardiovascular system.
你想说什么
What are you saying?
只有我们才能活着靠近时空之门
We may be the only ones who can survive around that portal,
才能无所顾忌地接近那艘科技堡垒去关掉它
the only ones who can get close enough to this Technodrome to shut it down.
警察还在抓我们呢 认为我们是怪物
But how? We're being hunted. They think we're monsters.
我们必须取得警方的支持
Yeah, we're gonna need the cops at our backs.
他们一直在搜捕我们
They're trying to lock us up.
除非
Unless...
一小口 能让我们的内部保持不变
One sip, and we'll stay the same on the inside,
只是外形变成了人类
but look like humans on the outside.
你们的少年时代就要结束了
Your boyhood is drawing to an end.
即将成为一名青年
You are becoming young men.
怎么选 自己决定
The choice is yours.
我尊重你们的选择
I'll do whatever you guys say.
决定吧
It's your call.
确定他们会来
You're sure they're coming?
我确定
They're coming.
- 不要开枪 - 不要开枪
- Hold your fire. - Hold your fire.
不要开枪
Hold your fire.
你们是什么
What are you?
这个问题可有点复杂
We're not really into labels.
有人叫我们怪物或者怪胎
Some call us freaks. Monsters.
简单地说 我们四兄弟来自纽约
Let's just say we're four brothers from New York
痛恨暴恐 热爱这座城市
who hate bullies and love this city.
现在我们是这座城市最大的希望
And right now, we're the city's best hope.
我为什么要相信你们
Why should I believe you?
你用不着相信我们
You don't have to take it from us.
信他就行了
Take it from him.
说话呀 弗恩
Go ahead, Vern.
说说你们的约定
Tell her about the arrangement.
什么约定啊
What arrangement?
和他们的约定
That... Arrangement.
听着 猎鹰还是猎鹰
Look, The Falcon is still The Falcon.
我只是接受过朋友的一点点帮助而已
I just may have gotten by with a little help from my friends.
这四位就是第一次抓住史莱德的人
These four are the ones who took Shredder down the first time.
我当时只是开车的
I was kind of more of a wingman.
为使这座城市摆脱黑暗
We've been doing our part to protect this city
我们出过力
from the shadows.
而现在我们更应该挺身而出
And we think we have something to offer.
- 我们需要 - 策略
- We're gonna need... - Strategy.
直觉
Instinct.
理智
Logic.
还要齐心协力
And boatloads of heart.
上车
Load up!
爱普尔 凯西还有弗恩需要护送到90号码头
April, Casey and Vern need an escort to Pier 90.
时空之门的电磁波就是从那儿发出的
The electromagnetic force of the portal is coming from there.
我发给你具体的坐标
Forwarding you the coordinates.
我们走
Send a team!
带我们去克莱斯勒大厦
Take us to the Chrysler Building.
我们会登上朗格的飞船上 把他打回老家去
We'll make our way up to his ship and take down Krang on his home turf.
快 奥尼尔 上车
Come on, O'NeiI, get in!
我给你的盔甲安装了呼吸系统
I installed a breathing apparatus in your helmet.
这样就可以在科技堡垒的大气环境下
This will help us survive the unique atmosphere
不用担心呼吸问题了
of the assembling Technodrome.
我还给你安装了一套手动传送装置
And I made a handheld version of the teleportation devi...
我们太伟大了 这是无可争辩的
Look at what we've done. This is undeniable.
后世将把我们奉若神明
We'll be gods to future generations.
我才是神
I'll be a god.
你还将是原来的你
You'll be just what you've always been.
是什么
What's that?
是蜡蚁
A footnote.
- 不 - 把他送回东京去
- No. - Take him to our facility in Tokyo.
不 你不能这样对我
No! No! No! No! No! You can't do this to me!
不 你怎么 不 我对你忠心耿耿
No, you... No. No, you will... No!
你答应过我 不 我是个天才 你会
I've done everything you asked! You promised! No!
不 我将名垂千古
I am a legend! I will be... No! I will be a legend!
你不能这样对我
You cannot do this to me.
世界会记住我的名字的
The world will know my name!
没人会知道你是谁
No one will ever know who you are.
90秒后到达
We're 90 seconds out.
所有的战术装备 武器 通讯器材全都准备就绪了
I've got tactical gear, weapons, communications standing by.
掩护我们登上飞船就行了
All we need is cover to get up there.
接下来我们需要找到
When we do, we've got to find that beacon
那个指引飞行器聚集的灯塔
that's drawing all those pieces together.
如果我们能成功地搞定灯塔
If we can send that beacon back to where it came from,
爱普尔 凯西还有弗恩就可以在我们的指令下关闭时空之门
and April, Casey and Vern can close that portal on our command...
- 永别了 科技堡垒 - 再见 朗格
- Good-bye, Technodrome. - Good-bye, Krang.
齐心协力
Team effort.
好了 他们分开了
All right, they're splitting up.
等等 我们在跟着乌龟走
Wait, we aren't going with the turtles?
为什么要跟他们走
Why aren't we going with the turtles?
只要一有什么事 你就只会想到那些乌龟
When something bad happens, you want to be with the turtles!
朗格指挥官
Commander Krang.
你来了 史莱德
There you are, Shredder!
我以为你根本来不了呢
I thought you'd never get here.
按你的要求 灯塔已经建好了
As you asked, the beacon has been set.
一旦科技堡垒彻底完工 我们就能统治这个星球了
And once the Technodrome reassembles, we can rule the planet.
你说什么 我们
I'm sorry. "We"?
你说我们
"We" will rule?
我们合作得很好
We were a team.
合作得很好
"We were a team!"
可惜 合作结束了
Teams are for the weak.
搭档就是用来骗的
Family is for the scared.
地球就是我的玩具
The Earth is my toy!
我不喜欢跟别人分享
And I do not like to share!
你敢耍我
You betrayed me!
说实话 我根本没把你当回事儿
Actually, I barely even thought about you.
装到玩具箱里跟那些破玩具放在一起吧
Back in the toy chest with the rest of the things I've broken.
渺小的地球人
Silly little earthling.
真是可笑
Goodbye.
玩玩新游戏吧
Now for a new game.
小心了 地球人 游戏开始了
Look out, Earth! It's playtime.
快 快跟上 前进
Move it, let's go!
快快快 各组迅速就位
Go, move, move, move. Get your team in position!
盾牌准备
Shields up!
- 好了 让他们进去吧 - 呈密集队形推进
- Okay, let's get them in. - Tight form on that barricade!
走 继续前进
Advance!
保持队形
Keep it tight!
- 凯西 - 坐稳了
- Casey! - Hold on!
冲进去
I'm going in.
不 当心 凯西
Casey! Casey!
这东西已经完成一大半了
This thing's 57% complete.
如果现在不阻止它
If we don't stop it now,
恐怕几分钟后就来不及了
it's gonna be ready to go in less than four minutes.
伙计们 还等什么呢
Guys, what are we waiting for?
- 你能行吗 - 行
- Hey. You got this? - Yeah.
没问题
I got this.
冲浪开始了
Surf's up, New York!
- 你听见了吗 - 听见什么
- Do you hear that? - Hear what?
声音好奇怪
It sounds strange.
比天上的外星人飞船还奇怪吗
Like "alien spacecraft in the sky" strange?
不
No.
是这种奇怪
That kind of strange.
留点儿神 别让外人溜进来
We've got to keep our eyes out for intruders.
到底什么样的是外人
Well, what do intruders look like?
除了疣猪和犀牛都是外人
Anybody that's not a big pig ora big rhino.
伙计们 听着
Oh, boy. Listen.
你们去控制传送装置
You guys secure the portal device.
我对付他们俩
I'll deal with those two.
控制传送装置 你什么意思
"Secure the portal device"? What does that even mean?
意思就是搞定所有守卫的人
It means kick the butt of anyone that's guarding it,
只要多尼一发信号 就关闭它
wait for Donnie's go signal, and shut it down.
可是都不知道有多少人在守卫
Yeah, but we don't know how many people are guarding it!
那咱俩换过来
Well, do you want to switch?
好吧 我们去控制装置
Yeah, no. We're gonna secure the portal.
早就知道
I thought so.
小子们
Hey, fellas!
还认识我吗
Remember me?
- 原来是他呀 - 笨警察 你头不晕了
- Look who it is. - Hey, cop, how's your noggin?
- 来呀 - 如你所愿
- Come on! - As you wish.
我来了 宝贝儿
It's on, baby!
超声波扫描发现
Ultrasonic scanners indicate
灯塔就在指挥舱前面
the beacon's location is somewhere near the command module
几百英尺的地方
a few hundred feet ahead.
好吧 我们得阻止那东西完成组装
Okay. We've got to stop this thing from completing.
怎么才能阻止它
And how are we supposed to do that?
那就先拿他开刀
Let's start with whatever that thing is.
那肯定是朗格
That must be Krang.
好了 呈战斗队形
All right, fall in, guys!
还不算糟 破机器人而已
It's not that bad, it's just a dumb robot.
比我想象的可差得远了
I was expecting way worse.
你觉得应该是什么样的
And what would that look like?
不知道 也许应该有胡子吧
I don't know, like a moustache maybe?
比如说邪恶的山羊胡什么的
Evil goatee or something. You know what I'm saying?
就像嚼过的口香糖 还有脸
It's like a chewed-up piece of gum! With a face!
我只警告你们一次 从我的飞船上滚开
I'll only warn you once. Get off my ship!
多尼 去控制台
Donnie, get to the console.
我们把这个讨厌的东西送回老家去
Let's send this jacked-up disco ball back where it came from.
口香糖先生 让我们看看你的本事吧
Hey, Bubblicious, let's see what you've got.
你们会大开眼界的 来吧
I'll show you what I've got! This!
这家伙比我想象的厉害
This dude's tougher than I thought.
你尽情地跑吧
You better run!
在比博的手里你是跑不掉的
You cannot escape the Bebop!
什么 我不去
What? Why me?
我们走 走啊 麦奇
Let's go! Come on, Mikey!
你完蛋了 朗格
You're going down, Krang!
麦奇 下来
Mikey, duck!
好了 还有九十秒飞船就组装完成了
Okay. About ninety seconds before this thing is complete.
就看你的了 多尼
All you, Donnie.
我不紧张
No pressure, no pressure, no pressure.
我真的好期待能抓住你们几个
You know, I'm looking forward to enslaving you.
满满一笼子甲鱼肯定很好玩
A cage full of tortoises might be nice.
我们是乌龟 不是什么甲鱼 根本不是一回事
We're turtles, not tortoises! There's a big difference.
对 神龟斩
Yeah. Turtles bite!
不
No!
开玩笑的
Just kidding.
你们想不到我还有这个吧
You don't think I've got spares for this?
伙计们 他的手臂能自动修复
Guys, he is literally rearming.
抓住你了 蠢货
Gotcha, pipsqueak!
哪儿去了
You see him, Rock?
你是跑不掉的
We know you're here somewhere.
- 多尼 - 再坚持十秒钟
- Donnie! - Just give me ten seconds.
这家伙实在太大了 我驾驭不了
Guys? I don't think I'm tall enough to ride this ride!
这些愚蠢的小爬虫
Stupid reptiles!
莱昂 当心
Leo, hang on!
你是我认为最讨厌的人
You're starting to be a real pain in my butt.
知道我是怎么对待讨厌的人的吗
And do you know what Bebop does with pains in his butt?
过来 讨厌的家伙
Get over here, little boy.
放下你那破球杆
Put down that popsicle stick.
比赛开始了 宝贝儿
Game on, baby!
看 那就是传送装置
Look. There's the portal device.
太好了 她手上有剑
Great. She has a sword.
我们有轮毅
We have a hubcap.
灯塔在哪儿 多尼 时间不多了
Where's the beacon, Donnie? We're running out of time!
你们就准备好
You already have.
看着我摧毁你们的城市吧
Prepare to watch your city crumble.
怎么回事 多尼
What's happening, Donnie?
我说对了 这是一个大能量武器系统
I was right. It's a massive weapons system.
朗格正在激活它
He's bringing it online!
找到了 找到灯塔了
I got it! I found the beacon! It's just
它就在那儿
up there.
- 麦奇 上 - 好的 我来搞定那灯
- Mikey, go! - I'll get that beacon.
好了 小家伙们
Okay, turtles.
现在该上大餐了
Time for the big guns.
游戏时间已经结束了
Play time is over!
太刺激了
I'm vertical!
想再刺激点儿吗
You want some, too?
我拿到了
I got it!
抓住他 罗克
Get him, Rock!
停
Stop, stop!
不
No.
- 罗克 - 怎么 比博
- Rock. - Yeah, Beebs?
也许下次应该扔回去
Maybe next time, throw it back.
来吧
Come on.
抓住 多尼
Hey! Heads up, Donnie.
灯
The beacon!
过来吧 你这小乌龟
Come here, little turtle.
来跟我拥抱一下
Let me give you a hug.
说再见吧
Good-bye.
好吧
Okay.
拉斐尔 跟我来
Raph! With me!
- 帮帮我 伙计们 - 坚持住 兄弟
- Little help, guys! - Hang on, little bro!
没人可以随便
Nobody messes...
动我的兄弟
With Mikey!
不
No!
伙计们 朗格完蛋了 但飞船还在组装
Guys, Krang is down, but his ship's still building.
多尼
Donnie!
无人机就绪
Drone activated.
马上就要闭合了
It's gonna be close.
成功了
Yes!
成功了 好了 伙计们 我们该下去关闭时空之门了
All right, guys, let's get off this ship and get that portal closed.
好了 我们已经到站了
Okay, this is our stop.
多尼 准备去关闭时空之门
Donnie, get ready to close the portal.
我会回来的 乌龟们
I'll be back, turtles,
你们就等着我的报复吧
a thousand times stronger!
关闭发送器 听见了吗
Close the portal! Close the portal!
伙计们 快动手
Guys, are you there? Guys, now!
关闭发送装置
Close the portal now!
太酷了
It's cool. It's cool.
是啊 我就知道能行
Yeah, I knew that would work.
等等 你真觉得我们四个少年
Wait, so you seriously thought us four teenagers
能拯救整个世界吗
could save the whole world?
当然 伙计们
Sure.
我们有这世上独一无二的
Guys, we got something no one else has.
- 神龟的力量 - 垃圾清扫车
- Turtle power! - Garbage truck!
垃圾清扫车
Garbage truck?
- 不是这个 我觉得应该喊 - 再想想 好吧
- Well, we do have one. - The other one.
神龟的力量
Turtle power!
日前逃脱的罪犯比博和罗斯泰迪
Escaped convicts Bebop and Rocksteady
已经被成功的缉拿归案
are now in police custody,
而巴克斯特·斯多克曼博士仍然在逃
while Dr. Baxter Stockman remains at large.
官方正式宣布城市已经重获安宁
Authorities assure us that the city is once again safe,
但是上周的事件仍然留下许多疑问
however questions remain about last week's events.
天空中出现的到底是什么 是怎么出现在我们这里的
What was that threat from the sky and how exactly was it averted?
不过最大的问题是我们该不该考虑
But the bigger question is, does it even matter?
给我们的英雄一个合法的身份
Do we need to give our heroes a name and a face?
还是仅仅知道
Or is it enough to know that they're out there
他在黑暗之中守护着我们就够了呢
watching over us from the shadows?
为了表彰你们为城市作出的贡献
For your incredible valor within this community,
同时也是你们跟警方密切合作的鼓励
and for your uncompromising cooperation with this agency,
特授予你们城市金钥匙
I present to you the keys to the city,
象征着我们的赞赏
a symbol of our appreciation,
和尊敬
respect,
献给我们的英雄们
and for our continued partnership.
他们是英雄的
To you brothers,
莱昂纳多
Leonardo,
拉斐尔 多纳泰罗 米开朗基罗
Raphael, Donatello, Michelangelo...
没有姓吗
Last name?
这个真没有
Not so much.
还真没想过 不公平
I never thought of that. That's no fair.
祝贺英雄们
Congratulations.
我也有一个 没什么
I got one of those. No big deal.
我帮过他们 我们是朋友
I helped them. They're friends of mine.
下周有什么安排吗
So, you got plans next weekend?
一般就是打冰球
Just my regular hockey game.
你想来看看吗
Do you want to come watch me play?
看看 我要跟你一对一打
Watch? I'll take you one on one.
你会输得很惨
And I'll kick your butt.
我很期待
I bet you will.
多尼 我的钥匙最大
My key's totally bigger.
比你们的都大 我的最大
It's bigger than your key, man. I got the big key.
我认为你们应该多露露面
I think you should give people more credit.
大家已经接受你们了
They'll accept you now.
也许你说得对
You're probably right.
但是
But...
我决定我们还是应该遵守约定
I think we'll stick with the arrangement we've had.
需要我们的时候 爱普尔知道去哪儿找我们
If you ever need us, April knows where to find us.
真的吗
Really?
你们可以过上正常的生活
You could live a normal life,
就跟我们一样
like the rest of us.
正常
Normal?
那多没意思
What fun is that?
耶
Yeah!
《忍者神龟2：破影而出》